sem-tracking-analytics.com 2015-03-28

# Engine Yard Privacy Policy

## Engine Yard Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement sets forth Engine Yard’s information gathering and dissemination practices regarding personal information collected by Engine Yard directly from individuals (“you”) in connection with the website located at [www.engineyard.com](http://www.engineyard.com/) and related URLs (“Website”).

#### What We Collect

Engine Yard may collect various types of personal information from you in connection with the Website. Such data may include identifying information and contact information (names, titles, addresses, phone and fax numbers, and email addresses), financial and payment information, information about products and services ordered or provided, IP addresses, and other transaction-related data.

#### How We Use Collected Information

###### Contact Information

We may use personal information collected in connection with the Website to contact you regarding products or services you have ordered or are receiving, to send you information about Engine Yard or its partners, to provide services to you, and for other purposes related to our business. You may choose to opt out of receiving communications from us. You will be given this choice at the points on the Website where we request your information. If you do not wish to receive future marketing mailings, please send an e-mail to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com).

###### Financial Information

We may ask you to provide your credit card or other financial account information to enable us to charge your account when you purchase services from us. All information you will be asked to provide is protected during transmission using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption to prevent it from being intercepted as it is transferred over the Internet. We provide this information only to third parties involved in processing payments for the services we provide and as otherwise provided in this Privacy Statement.

###### IP Addresses

We use your unique network address, or IP address, to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the Website.

###### Cookies

We may use cookies to keep track of your activities on the Website. We also use them to recognize return visitors and to track our promotions.

#### Disclosure Of Collected Information

Engine Yard may disclose to third parties information we collect from you in connection with the Website (i) as necessary to provide services requested by you, (ii) as necessary to process payments, (iii) to our subcontractors, service providers and other agents in connection with the provision of services to you (provided such subcontractors and service providers are under a duty to maintain the confidentiality of such information), and (iv) in connection with requests from law enforcement officials, government agencies, or otherwise as required in connection with legal proceedings. In addition, we may transfer information we collect from you to a third party in connection with a merger or sale of our business or assets, in which case the resulting entity or transferee will be permitted to obtain and use such information subject to the terms of this Privacy Statement.

#### Contact

If you would like to contact Engine Yard regarding the use of your personal information collected in connection with the Website, the types of third parties to whom we disclose such information, ways to limit the use and disclosure of such personal information, or to access, correct, amend, or delete your personal information collected in connection with the Website that is stored on our systems, please send an email to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com) with your request.

#### Safe Harbor Compliance

As part of our commitment to protecting your privacy, Engine Yard has elected to adhere to the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce (collectively, the “Safe Harbor Principles”) with respect to the collection, use and retention of personal data collected by Engine Yard directly from residents of European Union member countries and Switzerland. By certifying this election with the Department of Commerce, Engine Yard has declared that it intends to provide privacy protection with respect to such personal data in accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor Principles, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

For information regarding Engine Yard’s processing of personal data that is stored on Engine Yard’s servers at the direction of Engine Yard’s customers and their end users located in European Union member countries and Switzerland (and that is not collected by Engine Yard directly from individuals via the Website), please see the Engine Yard EU Safe Harbor Privacy Policy located at <http://www.engineyard.com/policies/eusafeharborpolicy>.

#### Linked Sites

The Website contains links to external websites. Engine Yard is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party websites.

#### Security

Engine Yard implements industry-standard security measures designed to prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, destruction or alteration of the personal information we collect via the Website.

#### Updates

Engine Yard may update this Privacy Statement from time to time to reflect changes in its services and customer feedback, and such changes shall become effective promptly after they are posted. Engine Yard encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of any changes. This Privacy Statement was last updated on August 28, 2012.
